A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller, Jr. family photographs, Series 1005 FA449
Rockefeller Archive Center
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. family photographs, Series 1005
1875-1969 (Bulk: 1910-1969)
1910-1969
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (John Davison), 1874-1960
Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich
FA449
60.66 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate.
Approximately 9,662 prints and lantern slides.
Arrangement
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series: Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
Other Finding Aids
For other Rockefeller family photographic holdings, please see the following finding aids:
FA445 Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001
FA446 William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002
FA447 John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003
FA448 William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004
FA450 Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006
FA451 John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007
FA454 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Series 1008
FA452 Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009
FA453 David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
The John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005 photographically documents all aspects of John D. Rockefeller Jr's life and career including family life, philanthropic activities and events, business activities and associates, real estate interests, and religious interests. The family-related images include individual and group portraits of his immediate family -- namely his wife Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and their six children -- Abby Mauze, John D. Rockefeller 3rd., Winthrop Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller and David Rockefeller, as well as a selection of relatives. The collection also contains images of the Rockefeller family homes, primarily their residences in New York and Seal Harbor, Maine as well as images of family trips and travel throughout Europe, Asia, the Middle East and the American West.
The collection spans a variety of formats including: prints, oversized prints, albums, and lantern slides.
Photographs
- John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, 1005
  Arrangement
  This series contains 2 subseries:
  1005A Abby Rockefeller Mauze family. 1005E Winthrop Rockefeller family.
  For ease of access the material is further arranged by:
  Prints (Boxes P 1, P 2, P 3, etc.). Albums (Boxes A 1, A 2, A 3, etc.). Oversized (Boxes: O 1, O 2, O 3, C 1, C 2, C 3, etc.).
  - Prints, 1875-1988; 25.46 Cubic Feet; 3,981 prints
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1870s-1922; 21 images (Box P 53)
      Scope and Contents
      Formal portraits
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1870s-1947; 32 prints (Box P 54)
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Koshiba Proofs, 21 prints (Box P 55)
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Philanthropies, 1918-1926; 8 prints (Box P 55)
      Includes but not limited to: Red Cross, Rhode Island Society of Colonial Dames.
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Philanthropies - Bayway Community, 1920-1926; 2 prints (Box P 55)
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Art Collections, 1924-1957; 13 prints. (Box P 55)
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Memorabilia - Museum of Rhode Island History, 1979; 1 print (Box P 157, Folder 11)
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Rhode Island School of Design - Lucy Truman Aldrich Collection, 1964-1971; 5 prints, 8x10 (Box P 157, Folder 12)
    - Art Collections, 1 print (Box P 159, Folder 1)
    - Art Collections, 1 print (Box P 159, Folder 2)
    - Art Collections, 8 prints (Box P 159, Folder 3)
    - Art Collections, 4 prints (Box P 159, Folder 4)
    - Art Collections, 1 print (Box P 159, Folder 5)
    - Art Collections, 1 print (Box P 159, Folder 6)
    - Art Collections, 1 print (Box P 159, Folder 7)
    - Art Collections, 9 prints (Box P 159, Folder 8)
    - Art Collections, 11 prints (Box P 159, Folder 9)
    - Art Collections, 4 prints (Box P 159, Folder 10)
    - Art Collections, 1 print (Box P 159, Folder 11)
    - Art Collections, 2 prints (Box P 159, Folder 12)
    - Art Collections, 2 prints (Box P 159, Folder 13)
    - Art Collections, 1 print (Box P 159, Folder 14)
    - Art Collections, 1924-1930; 3 prints (Box P 159, Folder 15)
    - Art Collections, 1 print (Box P 159, Folder 16)
    - Children Album 1, 1904-1907; 144 prints (Box P 56)
      Tarrytown, Hamptons, Beverly Farms, Warwick
    - Children Album 2, 1908-1909; 91 prints (Box P 57)
      Seal Harbor, Bar Harbor, Pocantico Hills, Lakewood, NJ, 10 and 13 West 54th Street, NYC
    - Children Album 2, 1908-1909; 74 prints. (Box P 58)
      Seal Harbor, Maine and Pocantico Hills, NY
    - Children Album 3, 1910-1912; 113 prints. (Box P 59)
      Seal Harbor and Pocantico Hills.
    - Children Album 4, 1912-1922; 145 prints. (Box P 60)
      Maine, Pocantico Hills, and New York City.
    - Children Album 5, 1917-1922; 136 prints (Box P 61)
      Seal Harbor, Pocantico Gills, Lakewood, NJ and New York City.
    - Children Album 6, 1922-1924; 73 prints (Box P 62)
      Maine, Pocantico Hills and New York City.
    - Children - Saturday Evening Post Series, 1950 November; 2 prints (Box P 157, Folder 13)
    - Children - Saturday Evening Post Series, 1950 November; approximately 50 prints (Box P 157, Folder 14-14C)
    - Family Album 1 - Koshiba Proofs, 1916-1932; 47 prints (Box P 63)
      Portraits of JDR Jr,, JDR Jr. with Abby, JDR Jr. with children, Abby with children, JDR Sr. and JDR Jr with children.
    - Family Album 2, 1915-1921; 97 prints (Box P 64)
    - Family Album 2, 1915-1926; 104 prints (Box P 65)
    - Friends, 1900s-1954; 16 prints (Box P 66)
    - Friends, 1915-1953; 20 prints (Box P 163)
    - Brothers, 1938-1967; 6 prints (Box P 66)
    - Group Portraits - Children, 1910-1967; 50 prints (Box P 67)
    - Group Portraits - Children, circa 1945; 3 prints (Box P 157, Folder 15)
    - Group Portraits - Children (with Abby Rockefeller Mauze), 1917; 1 print, 8x10 (Box P 157, Folder 16)
    - Group Portraits - Children (with Abby Rockefeller Mauze) - CBS Program, 1973; 6 prints, 8x10 (Box P 157, Folder 17)
    - Group Portraits - Children - JDR 3rd and David Rockefeller, 1967; 1 print (Box P 157, Folder 18)
    - Group Portraits - Children - Little Rock, Arkansas, circa 1952; 14 prints, 8x10 (Box P 157, Folder 19)
    - Group Portraits - Children - National Institute of Social Science, 1967; 8 prints, 8x10 (Box P 157, Folder 20)
    - Group Portraits - Family (with John D. Rockefeller), 1910-1936; 57 prints (Box P 68)
    - Group Portraits - Family (with John D. Rockefeller) - Owego, NY, 1 print (Box P 157, Folder 21)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 1904-1957; 55 prints (Box P 69)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 47 prints (Box P 70)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 1986; 2 prints, 8x10 color (Box P 157, Folder 22)
    - Group Portraits - Family - Christmas, 1947-1976; 36 prints (Box P 71)
    - Group Portraits - Family - Dedication of NAR College, 1982; 3 prints (Box P 157, Folder 23)
    - Group Portraits - Family - Rockefeller Center, 1984; 4 prints, 8x10 (Box P 157, Folder 24)
    - Group Portraits - Family and Friends, 1885-1957; 46 prints (Box P 72)
    - Group Portraits - Miscellaneous, 1922-1947; 4 prints (Box P 72)
    - Homes - Seal Harbor, 1914-1953; 55 prints (Box P 73)
    - Homes - Seal Harbor - Eyrie Oriental Garden, 1928-1950s; 15 prints (Box P 73)
    - Homes - Seal Harbor - Eyrie Oriental Garden, 1920s-1930s; 35 prints (Box P 157, Folder 25)
    - Homes - Seal Harbor - Eyrie Oriental Garden, 1950s; 17 prints, color (Box P 157, Folder 26)
    - Homes - Seal Harbor - Eyrie Oriental Garden - Building, 1920s-1930s; 35 prints (Box P 157, Folder 27)
    - Homes - JY Ranch, 4 prints (Box P 74)
    - Homes - 10 West 54th Street, 1894-1925; 6 prints. (Box P 74)
      Also some modern photos of the art gallery.
    - Homes - 10 West 54th Street, 2 prints (Box P 157, Folder 24A)
    - Homes - 10 West 54th Street - Furnishings, 1922; 26 prints (Box P 159, Folder 17)
    - Homes - 13 West 54th Street, 4 prints (Box P 74)
    - Homes - Williamsburg, VA, 3 prints (Box P 74)
    - Homes - 740 Park Avenue, 1971 January-February (Box P 75)
      Photographer - Bob Wands
    - JDR Jr - Account Books, 1885-1892; 5 prints (Box P 76)
    - JDR Jr - Brown University, 1895-1937; 17 prints (Box P 76)
    - JDR Jr - Brown University - JDR Jr Library Album, 1959-1964; 15 prints (Box P 76)
    - JDR Jr - Business, 1914-1940s; 15 prints (Box P 77)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Associates, 1921-1948; 39 prints (Box P 77)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Colorado Fuel and Iron Company, 1915-1929; 36 prints (Box P 78)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Colorado Fuel and Iron Company, 1915-1925; 34 prints (Box P 79)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Colorado Fuel and Iron Company, 1915; 22 prints (Box P 80)
      Photos from report regarding possible YMCA service in the mining community.
    - JDR Jr - Business - Dunbar, 11 prints (Box P 80)
      Dunbar Apartments and Dunbar National Bank
    - JDR Jr - Business - Forest Hill, 1930; 24 prints (Box P 80)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Industrial Labor Conference, 1915-1919; 8 prints (Box P 81)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Industrial Relations Hearings, 1915 January; 21 prints (Box P 81)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Industrial Relations Hearings, 1915; 1 print (Box P 158, Folder 28)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Offices, 20 prints (Box P 81)
      26 Broadway and Room 5600, 30 Rockefeller Plaza
    - JDR Jr - Business - Offices, 1 print (Box P 158, Folder 29)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Oil Lease Investigation, 1928; 11 prints (Box P 82)
    - JDR Jr - Business - 17 West 54th Street, 7 prints (Box P 82)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Radio City Music Hall, 1932-1937; 6 prints (Box P 82)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Rockefeller Center, 1931-1962; Approximately 35 prints (Box P 83)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Rockefeller Center, 1932-1967; 38 prints (Box P 84)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Rockefeller Center, 3 prints (Box P 158, Folder 30)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Rockefeller Center - Group Portrait, 1940; 1 print (Box P 158, Folder 31)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Rockefeller Center - Guy Essyell, 1963; 2 prints (Box P 158, Folder 32)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Rockefeller Center - National Historic Landmark Ceremony, 1988; 1 print (Box P 158, Folder 33)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Rockefeller Center - National Historic Landmark Ceremony, 1988; 1 print (Box P 158, Folder 34)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Rockefeller Center - Plaque, 1962; 25 prints (Box P 158, Folder 35)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Rockefeller Center - View of Rockefeller Center, 1950s; 32 prints (Box P 158, Folder 36)
    - JDR Jr - Candids, 9 prints (Box P 84)
    - JDR Jr - Cartoons, 1932; 3 prints (Box P 84)
      cartoons are from Fosdick biography of JDR Jr.
    - JDR Jr - Educational Interests, 1950s; 36 prints (Box P 85)
    - JDR Jr - Informals, 1910-1949; Approximately 40 prints (Box P 86)
    - JDR Jr - Informals, 1915-1940; Approximately 25 prints (Box P 87)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies, 1916-1961; 47 prints (Box P 88)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies, 1929-1958; 36 prints (Box P 89)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - American School of Oriental Research, 1936-1937; 2 prints (Box P 90)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Acadia National Park, 1922-1955; 28 prints (Box P 90)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - American Museum of Natural History, 1928-1931; 8 prints (Box P 90)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Associates, 1919-1960s; 16 prints (Box P 91)
      Primarily portraits
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Byrd Expedition, 1920s; 5 prints (Box P 91)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Cathedral of St John the Divine, 1915; 9 prints (Box P 91)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Cleveland Community Chest, 1946; 3 prints (Box P 91)
      Opening
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - French Restorations, 1924-1956; 38 prints (Box P 92)
      Primarily Versailles restoration 1936
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - French Restorations, 1927-1936; 31 prints (Box P 93)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Grand Teton National Park, 1930-1955; 46 prints (Box P 94)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Grand Teton National Park, 1933-1955; 21 prints (Box P 95)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Interchurch World Movement, 1920; 4 prints (Box P 96)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Jackson Hole Preserve, 1954; 2 prints (Box P 158, Folder 39)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Jerusalem Museum, 1950-1967; 43 prints (Box P 96)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Laboratory of Anthropology, 1929-1956; 28 prints (Box P 97)
      Santa Fe, New Mexico
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - League of Nations Library, 1932-1937; 18 prints (Box P 97)
      Primarily construction
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1928-1958; 28 prints (Box P 98)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Museum of Modern Art (MOMA), 1945-1956; 5 prints (Box P 98)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Museum of Modern Art (MOMA) - Construction, 1939; 17 prints (Box P 158, Folder 40)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Museum of Modern Art (MOMA) - 25th Anniversary, 1954 October 10; 12 prints (Box P 158, Folder 41)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Park Avenue Baptist Church, 1923-1928; 28 prints (Box P 98)
      Primarily Grand Carillon bells
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Peking Union Medical College (PUMC), 1921; 25 prints (Box P 99)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Red Cross, 1918; 2 prints (Box P 99)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Rhode Island School of Design, 1952-1954; 16 prints (Box P 99)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Riverside Church, 1929-1930; 39 prints (Box P 100)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Riverside Church, 1930; 2 prints (Box P 158, Folder 42)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Rockefeller University, 1 print (Box P 158, Folder 43)
      Campus
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Sleepy Hollow Restorations, 1937-1959; 64 prints (Box P 101)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Spelman College, 1956; 20 prints (Box P 158, Folder 44)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Spelman College - Fine Arts Building, 1964; 9 prints (Box P 158, Folder 45)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - United Nations, 1952; 5 prints (Box P 102)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - United Negro College Fund (UNCF), 1948-1955; 9 prints (Box P 102)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - University of Chicago, 1889-1941; 29 prints (Box P 102)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - United Service Organizations (USO), 1941-1947; 27 prints (Box P 103)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Williamsburg, 1927-1958; 55 prints (Box P 104)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Williamsburg - Children, 1955; 6 prints (Box P 158, Folder 37)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Williamsburg - Gaul (?), 1 print (Box P 158, Folder 38)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Yellowstone National Park, 1924, 1925, 1927; 39 prints (Box P 105)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Yellowstone National Park, 1928; 33 prints (Box P 106)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Yellowstone National Park, 1929; 50 prints (Box P 107)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Yosemite National Park, 1 print (Box P 107)
    - JDR Jr - Portraits, 1876-1950; 54 prints (Box P 108)
    - JDR Jr - Portraits, 1914-1950s; 31 prints (Box P 109)
    - JDR Jr - Prohibition, 1925; 2 prints (Box P 110)
    - JDR Jr - Real Estate Interests, 1919-1940; 49 prints (Box P 164)
    - JDR Jr - Real Estate Interests, 1920-1954; 55 prints (Box P 165)
    - JDR Jr - Religious Interests, 1917-1929; 5 prints (Box P 110)
    - JDR Jr - Signature, 1 print (Box P 110)
    - JDR Jr - Travel, 1953; 5 prints (Box P 110)
      Pictures by Horace Albright
    - JDR Jr - Travel - China, 1921; 37 prints (Box P 110)
    - JDR Jr - Travel - China, 1921; 31 prints (Box P 111)
    - JDR Jr - Travel - Egypt, 1929; 5 prints (Box P 111)
    - JDR Jr - Travel - France, 1924; 6 prints (Box P 111)
      Reception for rebuilding of Versailles Palace
    - JDR Jr - Travel - Panama Cruise, 1913 March; 6 prints (Box P 111)
    - JDR Jr - Whitehall Club, 1923; 4 prints (Box P 111)
      Squash
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller, 2 prints (Box P 112)
      Portraits
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller - Funeral, 1971 January 25; 6 prints (Box P 112)
      740 Park Avenue, NYC
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller - Homes - Hillcrest, 1970s; Approximately 100 prints and contact sheets (Box P 112)
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller, 38 prints (Box P 158, Folder 46)
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller, 9 prints (Box P 160)
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller - Family, 26 prints (Box P 160)
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller - Friends, 8 prints (Box P 160)
    - Relatives, 1937-1941; 2 prints (Box P 113)
    - Relatives - Aldrich Family, 41 prints (Box P 113)
    - Relatives - Aldrich Family, 32 prints (Box P 114)
    - Relatives - Aldrich Family - Homes, 1895-1949; 54 prints (Box P 115)
  - Albums, 1893-1969; Approximately 2,250 prints
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (AAR) - Art - Bernard Berenson Art Collection, 1956; 36 prints (Box A 15)
      Florence
    - AAR - Art - Scrapbook, 1925-1927; 150 prints (Box A 16)
      with associated correspondence, 1920s and 1956
    - AAR - AAR Memorial Album, 1948; 1 print (Box A 17)
    - AAR - Scrapbook, Warwick, Rhode Island, 1893 July 5 (Box A 18)
    - AAR - "Mother's Scrapbook", 400 prints (Box A 19)
    - AAR - Scrapbook (Box A 38)
    - Group Portraits - "Friends at Forest Hill, Pocantico Hills and the Bigelow House", circa 1900; 94 prints (Box A 1)
    - "Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller" (Family of Man Dinner), 1967 November 28; 12 prints (Box A 30)
      Given by the Protestant Council of the City of New York to JDR Jr. (posthumously) and other members of the Rockefeller family for their philanthropic activities.
    - Homes - Cleveland - Forest Hill Park, 1939 December; 30 prints (Box A 8)
    - Forest Hill Estate - Thomas Photographs (Box A 8A, Folder 1-5)
    - Homes - New York City - 740 Park Avenue Album (contains 10 and 12 West 54th Street), 1948; 40 prints (Box A 20)
    - Homes - New York City - 10 West 54th Street, 40 prints (Box A 21)
    - Homes - New York City - "4 and 10 West 54th Street", 1937; 60 prints and duplicates. (Box A 39)
    - Homes - New York City - "Additions to the House at 10 West 54th Street" (Welles Bosworth, Architect), 9 architectural drawings (Box A 40)
    - Homes - Seal Harbor - Seal Harbor Scenes, 20 prints (Box A 9)
      Photos taken by Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    - Homes - Seal Harbor - "The Eyrie", 2 copies.; 20 prints and duplicates (Box A 27)
    - Homes - Seal Harbor - "The Garden", 2 copies.; 37 prints and duplicates (Box A 28)
    - Homes - Seal Harbor - Eyrie Oriental Garden - "Sculpture in the Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Garden", 1969 September; 41 prints (Box A 29)
    - Homes - Seal Harbor - "Seal Harbor, 1935" (Acadia National Park), 25 prints (Box A 41)
    - Homes - Seal Harbor - "My Garden, Seal Harbor, 1935" (Box A 42)
    - JDR Jr - "Brown University", 16 prints (Box A 2)
    - JDR Jr - Brown University - "Brown '97 Sixtieth Reunion", 1957; 41 prints (Box A 10)
    - JDR Jr - Brown University - "JDR Jr", 1955; 31 prints (Box A 31)
    - JDR Jr - Brown University Library - "Mrs. John D. Rockefeller Jr", 1964 November 16; 30 prints (Box A 32)
    - JDR Jr - Business - "Trip through the Oil Fields", 1909; Approximately 50 prints (Box A 3)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Forest Hill Development, Approximately 75 prints and architectural drawings (Box A 22)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Forest Hill Homes, 77 prints (Box A 23)
    - JDR Jr - Business - Radio City Music Hall - "Rockettes in Paris", 1937; 51 prints (Box A 34)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - French Restorations - "Le Chateau de Versailles", 1924 July; 51 prints (Box A 35)
      Given to Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. by B. Chaussemiche, Architect of the Palace at Versailles
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - French Restorations - "Souvenir de la viste de Monsieur and Madame John D. Rockefeller Jr", 1936 June 30; 17 prints (Box A 36)
      Includes menu.
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - United Service Organization (USO) - "Williamsburg USO Dedication", 1943 May 6; 24 prints (Box A 24)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - United War Work Campaign, 1918 November; 38 prints (Box A 37)
    - JDR Jr - Philanthropies - Williamsburg - "Colonial Williamsburg After 25 Years", 1952; 50 prints (Box A 25)
    - JDR Jr - Travel - "Trip to Cuba", 1900 March; Approximately 90 prints (Box A 4)
    - JDR Jr - Travel - "Trip to Cuba" (Duplicate 1), 1900 March; Approximately 90 prints (Box A 5)
    - JDR Jr - Travel - "Trip to Cuba" (Duplicate 2), 1900 March; Approximately 90 prints (Box A 6)
    - JDR Jr - Travel - "Jr's Trip to England", 75 prints (Box A 7)
    - JDR Jr - Travel - "Trip to California and Alaska", 1899; 130 prints (Box A 11)
    - JDR Jr - Travel - "Trip to Egypt", 1929; 6 prints (Box A 12)
    - JDR Jr - Travel - Camping Album, 95 prints (Box A 26)
    - JDR Jr - Travel - "Trip to Europe" (Holland), 52 prints (Box A 33)
    - JDR Jr - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1915-1940" (Box A 43A)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Box A 43A is restricted from scholarly access due to preservation concerns. Contains original images.
    - JDR Jr - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1915-1940" (Box A 43B)
      Box A 43B is restricted from scholarly access due to preservation concerns. Contains original images.
    - JDR Jr - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1915-1940" (Box A 43C)
      Contains photocopies of the album.
    - Relatives - Aldrich family - Homes - "Warwick" (Rhode Island), 1899; 42 prints (Box A 14)
  - Oversized, 1890-1967; 10 Cubic Feet; Approximately 800 prints
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 17 prints (Box O 1)
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1908-1947; 7 prints and duplicates (Box O 13)
    - Friends, 2 prints (Box O 23)
    - Group Portraits - Brothers, 1939-1958; 2 prints (Box O 2)
    - Group Portraits - Brothers, 1949-1958; 9 prints (Box O 3)
    - Group Portraits - Brothers, 1967; 9 prints (Box O 4)
      National Institute of Social Sciences dinner
    - Group Portraits - Brothers, 1967; 14 prints (Box O 5)
    - Group Portraits - Children, 1949-1957; 8 prints (Box O 2)
    - Group Portraits - Children, 1950; 1 print (Box O 14)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 6 prints (Box O 6)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 11 prints (Box O 7)
    - Group Portraits - Family (Box C 7)
    - Group Portraits - Family - Koshiba, 8 prints (Box O 15)
    - Group Portraits - Family - Hill and Koshiba, 8 prints (Box O 16)
    - Group Portraits - Family (with John D. Rockefeller), 2 prints (Box O 6)
      with young David Rockefeller.
    - Group Portraits - Family (with John D. Rockefeller), 2 prints (Box O 7)
    - Group Portraits - Family (with John D. Rockefeller), 1 print (Box O 14)
    - Group Portraits - Family (with John D. Rockefeller), 13 prints (Box O 15)
    - Group Portraits - Family (with John D. Rockefeller), 6 prints (Box O 16)
    - Group Portraits - Family (with John D. Rockefeller) (Box C 6)